# Arthur Zherka

📍 Warsaw, PL 📞 (48) 792-586-234 📮 arthurzherko@gmail.com

**Full-stack Developer** with 7 years of experience. A result-oriented professional, following best practices to produce optimal solutions, great team player, interested in the development of PWA and architecture for change.

# **Technologies**

- JavaScript, TypeScript
- React, React Native, Next.js, Redux Toolkit, Webpack
- Node.js, Express, GraphQL, Web3

- MongoDB, Redis, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- AWS, Firebase

## **Experience**

## Senior Full-Stack Developer

#### **Viacry**

May 2023 - Feb 2024

www.genzeroaction.com - app enables Web3-based rewards ecosystems. Basic functionality: administration (creation, verification of evidence) of social actions necessary for advertising campaign of a certain company, the user receives a reward in the form of GENZERO tokens for performing social actions (plant a tree, share your climate story, etc.), which later he can exchange for products of the same company. After performing each action, the user is offered to get additional tokens by sharing the proof in social networks. In this way, the client receives advertising in social networks and users are rewarded for the work done.

- Designed the architecture of the project: Typescript, Next.js, Express.js, Magic.link, Web3, MongoDB, DigitalOcean, Infura, Brevo, PostHog
- Led a small team (4 people) in the development of an application
- Demonstrated the ability to resolve conflicts and manage project contingencies, which helped keep team motivation and productivity at a high level
- Developed backend (Express.js, MongoDB, Web3, Brevo, Magic.link, Mongoose)
- Developed Web3 based service to create, transfer and manage GENZERO token
- Developed variety (60+) of responsive components (SSR, Next.js)
- Implemented authorization service (next-auth)
- Implemented analytics tools for capturing user events (PostHog, GTM)

#### **Senior Frontend Developer**

#### Suno, Inc

**Sep 2022 - Apr 2023** 

Software for the Savvy Audiologist. Basic functionality: calendar to schedule an appointment with the audiologist, filling out a patient card, patient-doctor chat, internal shop to select and purchase hearing aids, creating pdf invoices, hearing aid performance comparison charts.

- Developed the website for audiology clinics across USA that allows you to make an appointment with doctors via the built-in event calendar (Typescript, React, Redux Toolkit, React Scheduler)
- Implemented SOAP note creation and editing with voice input, automatic creation of pdf reports (Lexical, microphone-stream, jsPDF)
- Maintained a friendly and open atmosphere within the team, which promoted a high degree of co-operation and efficiency in completing assigned tasks
- Developed a chat with infinite scrolling (WebSocket API)
- Developed interactive graphs, forms with draggable elements (chart.js, react-draggable, react-dnd)
- Developed a large number of components (100+) in a tight schedule
- Test coverage of each component and each feature (Cypress)

#### **Frontend Developer**

## **Lesido (contract with CodeControl)**

June 2021 – Jan 2023

app.lesido.de - Digital library of picture books and interactive video chat. A website and app that allows close relatives to interact with their children over long distances and learn to read together. Basic functionality: pdf book library, video chat, synchronisation of user actions (page turning, drawing).

The React Native application can be found on the German App Store by searching for "Lesido"

- Developed the website and React Native application for interactive book reading using modern technologies (Typescript, Hooks, SWR, Recoil)
- Effectively mentored within the team for two years to develop communication, problem solving and leadership skills in team members
- Implemented audio and video capabilities for the web and mobile application. (The Amazon Chime SDK)
- Implemented synchronisation of cursor, book pages, routing during a call between users (WebSocket API)
- Implemented a subscription system with a trial periods and discount coupons (Stripe)
- Developed Book Reader with lazy loading pages (react-pdf, react-window)
- Implemented a notification system using Firebase Cloud Messaging (FCM)
- Implemented analytics tools for capturing user events (PostHog, GTM)

Fractal - Accounting software for the analysis of the best purchase and sale options between trading platforms (EXANTE and BitMEX)

- Developed backend that interacted with the API of two trading platforms (EXANTE and BitMEX) finding suitable options for buying and selling instruments (GraphQL, Express)
- Led a small team (3 people) in the development of a web application to interact with the backend (GraphQL)
- Developed comparison table to show the best options for buying and selling instruments

#### **Full-stack Developer**

#### **Sportrecs (contract)**

Mar 2020 - Sep 2020

Sportrecs.com - Video broadcasts of sporting events. (Twitch for sport)

- Developed backend (GraphQL, Express, Razzle)
- Implemented a broadcast monitoring system (FPS, bandwidth, speed) with interactive level-of-detail rendering of large graphs (Chart.js)
- Developed the mechanism of creating and validation of widgets for partner sites

## Frontend Developer

#### **Maxiru** (contract)

Oct 2016 - Feb 2020

Virgin Voyages - Application to play media in cabin

- Rewrote the old frontend with a new, faster one using modern best practices and recent technologies (React, React Native)
- Implemented WebSockets in application for real-time dashboard updates
- Reduced project build time (more than 15 seconds) by reconfiguring Webpack
- Coordinated releases and the implementation of features
- Covered 80% of code with unit tests

Virgin Voyages - Application for online check-in, booking and just about everything smooth sailing

- Developed the application with a user-friendly UI (React Native, Redux Thunk, Webpack)
- Developed variety (50+) of responsive components
- Implemented biometric authentication, PIN code, document detection and photo editor
- Integrated wearable tech accessories (bracelets) via Bluetooth
- Developed CI/CD process for infrastructure (Jenkins)
- Developed animations (react-spring)

Maxiru - Map Editor project (web editor for vector graphics)

- Developed a web application for pathfinding and navigation on SVG map
- Developed UI components based on trigonometric formulas
- Achieved 80% code coverage for unit tests using Jest

Maxiru - Web simulator of an Unreal Engine 4 application

- Developed a real-time web app to display the simulated movement of the bots from Unreal Engine 4
- Designed and developed the core architecture of SPA based on client requirements (React, Redux Thunk, Immutable.js)
- Developed a web dashboard with editable spreadsheets and auto save

DeepVideo - Service for video that helps viewers to identify products

- Developed SPA (Angular 2 and D3.js) with responsive UI and interactive graphs (zoomable bar chart)
- Developed with Angular 2 editable spreadsheets with auto save, sorting, filters and search with autocomplete

Woo Club - Shoppable video platform project

- Developed a new variety (20+) of responsive, accessible and localizable UI components with Vue.js
- Integrated a 3rd party YouTube API with for the ability to add tags to on videos to display the products that appear in them

# Web Developer Freelance Jun 2015 - Sep 2016

- Developed 8 responsive landing pages (HTML, CSS, Javascript, Gulp)
- Cleaned up variety (10+) of hacked Wordpress sites (malware, spam, access recovery)

## **Education**

Bachelor's degree in Business Economics and Management, Polessky State University

Sep 2013 - Jul 2017